This is my great uncle,
هذا هو عمي الأكبر،
my father's father's younger brother.
الأخ الأصغر لجدي من جهة أبي.
His name was Joe McKenna.
اسمه جو ماكينا.
He was a young husband and a semi-pro basketball player
كان زوجا شابا ولاعب كرة سلة نصف محترف
and a fireman in New York City.
ورجل اطفاء في مدينة نيويورك.
Family history says he loved being a fireman,
طبقا لتاريخ العائلة، فقد أحب ذلك العمل
and so in 1938, on one of his days off,
لذا في عام 1938، في أحد أيام عطلته،
he elected to hang out at the firehouse.
اختار أن يتجول في محطّة الإطفاء.
To make himself useful that day, he started polishing all the brass,
وليجعل نفسه مفيدا ذلك اليوم، بدأ بتلميع النحاس
the railings on the fire truck, the fittings on the walls,
والدرابزين على عربة الاطفاء والمعدات على الحوائط.
and one of the fire hose nozzles,
عندئذ واحدة من صنابير خراطيم المياه
a giant, heavy piece of metal,
الضخمة، وهي قطعة ثقيلة من المعدن
toppled off a shelf and hit him.
سقطت من على الرف لترتطم به
A few days later, his shoulder started to hurt.
بعد عدة أيام، بدأ ذراعه يؤلمه.
Two days after that, he spiked a fever.
بعد ذلك بيومين أصيب بالحمى.
The fever climbed and climbed.
ارتفعت حرارته شيئا فشيئا.
His wife was taking care of him,
كانت زوجته تعتني به،
but nothing she did made a difference, and when they got the local doctor in,
ولكن لا شيء فعلته أحدث فرقا، وعندما استدعوا طبيب البلدة
nothing he did mattered either.
لا شيء فعله أحدث فرقا أيضا.
They flagged down a cab and took him to the hospital.
استقلوا سيارة أجرة وذهبوا به للمستشفى.
The nurses there recognized right away that he had an infection,
أدركت الممرضات على الفور أنه أصيب بعدوى،
what at the time they would have called "blood poisoning,"
كانت تعرف حينئذ باسم "تسمم الدم"،
and though they probably didn't say it,
و بالرغم من أنهم لم يقولوها
they would have known right away
إلا أنهم أدركوا على الفور
that there was nothing they could do.
انه لا يوجد شيء يمكنهم فعله.
There was nothing they could do because the things we use now
لم يكن بوسعهم فعل شيء لأن ما نستخدمه اليوم
to cure infections didn't exist yet.
لعلاج العدوى لم يكن موجودا بعد.
The first test of penicillin, the first antibiotic,
الاختبار الاول للبنسيلين- أول مضاد حيوي-
was three years in the future.
كان بعد ثلاث سنوات من ذالك الوقت.
People who got infections either recovered, if they were lucky,
الأشخاص الذين يصابون بالعدوى، إما أن يشفوا إن كانوا محظوظين،
or they died.
أو يموتوا.
My great uncle was not lucky.
عمي الأكبر لم يكن محظوظا.
He was in the hospital for a week, shaking with chills,
قضى أسبوعا في المشفى يعاني من الرجفان،
dehydrated and delirious,
ومصاب بالجفاف، والهذيان،
sinking into a coma as his organs failed.
ثم أصيب بغيبوبة بعدما توقفت أعضاؤه عن العمل.
His condition grew so desperate
أصبحت حالته ميؤس منها جدا
that the people from his firehouse lined up to give him transfusions
حتى أن زملاؤه في العمل اصطفوا للتبرع له بالدم
hoping to dilute the infection surging through his blood.
أملا في تخفيف العدوى المتدفقة في دمه.
Nothing worked. He died.
لم ينفع شيء. لقد مات.
He was 30 years old.
كان في الثلاثين من عمره.
If you look back through history,
إذا نظرت عبر التاريخ،
most people died the way my great uncle died.
كان معظم الناس يموتوا كما مات عمي الأكبر.
Most people didn't die of cancer or heart disease,
لم يمت معظم الناس بسبب السرطان أو أمراض القلب،
the lifestyle diseases that afflict us in the West today.
أمراض نمط الحياة التي تصيبنا اليوم في الغرب.
They didn't die of those diseases because they didn't live long enough
لم يموتوا بسبب تلك الامراض لأنهم لم يعيشوا طويلا كفاية
to develop them.
ليتطور لديهم المرض.
They died of injuries --
ماتوا من إصابات--
being gored by an ox,
كاصطدام ثور بهم،
shot on a battlefield,
أو تعرضهم لإصابة في معركة،
crushed in one of the new factories of the Industrial Revolution --
أو وقع سحقهم في أحد المصانع الجديدة في الثورة الصناعية
and most of the time from infection,
و في أغلب الأحيان من عدوى
which finished what those injuries began.
لتنهي ما بدأته تلك الاصابات.
All of that changed when antibiotics arrived.
تغير كل هذا مع ظهور المضادات الحيوية.
Suddenly, infections that had been a death sentence
فجأة، أصبحت العدوي التي كانت كحكم بالاعدام
became something you recovered from in days.
شيئا يمكن الشفاء منه في أيام
It seemed like a miracle,
بدى الأمر كمعجزة،
and ever since, we have been living inside the golden epoch of the miracle drugs.
و منذ ذلك الحين، ونحن نعيش في العصر الذهبي لهذه الأدوية الخارقة.
And now, we are coming to an end of it.
و الآن نحن على مشارف نهايته.
My great uncle died in the last days of the pre-antibiotic era.
مات عمي الأكبر في الأيام الأخيرة لعصر ما قبل المضادات الحيوية.
We stand today on the threshold of the post-antibiotic era,
واليوم نقف على عتبة عصر ما بعد المضادات الحيوية،
in the earliest days of a time when simple infections
في الأيام الأولى من العصر الذي ستكون فيه عدوى البسيطة
such as the one Joe had will kill people once again.
كالتي أصيب بها جو، قاتلة للبشر مرة أخرى.
In fact, they already are.
في الواقع، هي كذلك بالفعل.
People are dying of infections again because of a phenomenon
يموت ناس من العدوى مرة أخرى بسبب ظاهرة
called antibiotic resistance.
تسمى "مقاومة المضادات الحيوية."
Briefly, it works like this.
باختصار، فهي تعمل كالتالي
Bacteria compete against each other for resources, for food,
تنافس البكتيريا بعضها البعض من أجل الموارد، من أجل الطعام،
by manufacturing lethal compounds that they direct against each other.
بتصنيع مركبات قاتلة وتوجيهها ضد بعضها البعض.
Other bacteria, to protect themselves,
وبكتيريا أخرى لكي تحمي نفسها،
evolve defenses against that chemical attack.
تطور دفاعات ضد هذا الهجوم الكيميائي.
When we first made antibiotics,
عندما صنعنا المضادات الحيوية للمرة الأولى،
we took those compounds into the lab and made our own versions of them,
أخذنا هذه المركبات إلى المعمل وصنعنا نسختنا المعدلة منها
and bacteria responded to our attack the way they always had.
واستجابت البكتيريا لهجومنا كما تفعل دائما.
Here is what happened next:
إليكم ما حدث بعد ذلك
Penicillin was distributed in 1943,
تم توزيع البنسلين عام 1943،
and widespread penicillin resistance arrived by 1945.
ظهرت مقاومة واسعة النطاق للبنسيلين عام 1945.
Vancomycin arrived in 1972,
ظهر الفانكوميسين عام 1972،
vancomycin resistance in 1988.
مقاومة الفانكوميسين عام 1988.
Imipenem in 1985,
الإميبينيم عام 1985،
and resistance to in 1998.
مقاومته عام 1998.
Daptomycin, one of the most recent drugs, in 2003,
الدابتوميسين- أحد أحدث العقاقير- عام 2003،
and resistance to it just a year later in 2004.
و المقاومة ضده. عام 2004 عام واحد فقط بعد ذلك.
For 70 years, we played a game of leapfrog --
لـمدة 70 عاما، لعب لعبة القفزية
our drug and their resistance,
دواؤنا ومقاومتهم له،
and then another drug, and then resistance again --
ومن ثم دواء آخر، ثم مقاومتهم له مرة أخرى
and now the game is ending.
والآن شارفت اللعبة على الانتهاء
Bacteria develop resistance so quickly that pharmaceutical companies
تطور البكتيريا مقاومتها بسرعة جدا، حتى أن شركات الأدوية
have decided making antibiotics is not in their best interest,
قررت أن صناعة المضادات الحيوية ليس في مصلحتها،
so there are infections moving across the world
لذا توجد عدوى تنتشر عبر العالم
for which, out of the more than 100 antibiotics
لكل منها، من ضمن 100 مضاد حيوي
available on the market,
متاح في السوق،
two drugs might work with side effects,
لا يوجد إلا عقارين قد يتمكن من مواجهتها مع ظهور أعراض جانبية،
or one drug,
أو عقار واحد،
or none.
أو لا واحد منها.
This is what that looks like.
هذا ما يبدو عليه الوضع.
In 2000, the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, the CDC,
في عام 2000، مراكز السيطرة على الأمراض والوقاية منها (CDC)،
identified a single case
تعرفت على حالة مرضية
in a hospital in North Carolina
في مشفى في شمال كارولينا
of an infection resistant to all but two drugs.
لعدوى مقاومة لكل العقاقير إلا عقاران
Today, that infection, known as KPC,
اليوم تعرف هذه العدوى باسم KPC،
has spread to every state but three,
وقد انتشرت في جميع الولايات ما عدا ثلاث،
and to South America, Europe
كما انتشرت في أمريكا الجنوبية وأوروبا
and the Middle East.
والشرق الأوسط.
In 2008, doctors in Sweden
عام 2008، قام أطباء في السويد
diagnosed a man from India with a different infection
بتشخيص حالة رجل من الهند مصاب بعدوى مختلفة
resistant to all but one drug that time.
مقاومة لجميع العقاقير إلا واحد آنذاك.
The gene that creates that resistance,
عُرف الجين المسبب لتلك المقاومة
known as NDM, has now spread from India into China, Asia, Africa,
بـNDM. انتشر حاليا من الهند إلى الصين وآسيا وأفريقيا
Europe and Canada, and the United States.
وأوروبا وكندا والولايات المتحدة.
It would be natural to hope
سيكون طبيعي أن نأمل
that these infections are extraordinary cases,
أن هذه العَدوى حالات استثنائية،
but in fact,
لكن في الواقع،
in the United States and Europe,
في أمريكا وأوروبا،
50,000 people a year
50,000 شخص سنوياُ
die of infections which no drugs can help.
يموتون كل عام من عَدوى لا علاج لها.
A project chartered by the British government
بدأت الحكومة البريطانية مشروعا
known as the Review on Antimicrobial Resistance
عرف باسم بيان مقاومة المضادات الحيوية
estimates that the worldwide toll right now is 700,000 deaths a year.
يقدر تعداد الوفيات الآن بحوالي 700,000 في العام الواحد.
That is a lot of deaths,
هذا عدد كبيرمن الموتى،
and yet, the chances are good that you don't feel at risk,
مع ذلك هناك احتمال كبير أنك لا تشعر بخطورة الأمر،
that you imagine these people were hospital patients
و أنك تعتقد أن هؤلاء الناس كانوا مرضى في المستشفيات
in intensive care units
في العناية المركزة
or nursing home residents near the ends of their lives,
أو مرضى في منازلهم شارفت حياتهم على الانتهاء،
people whose infections are remote from us,
أناس نعتقد أن اصابتهم بالعدوى أمر لا يحصل لنا،
in situations we can't identify with.
في مواقف لا يمكننا التعرض لها.
What you didn't think about, none of us do,
ما لا تفكر فيه، لا أحد منا يفعل،
is that antibiotics support almost all of modern life.
أن المضادات الحيوية تدعم كل جوانب الحياة الحديثة.
If we lost antibiotics,
إذا فقدنا المضادات الحيوية،
here's what else we'd lose:
هذا ما يمكن أن، نفقده أيضا:
First, any protection for people with weakened immune systems --
أولاً. أي حماية لذوي الأجهزة المناعية الضعيفة
cancer patients, AIDS patients,
مرضى السرطان والايدز
transplant recipients, premature babies.
ومتلقي الأعضاء والأطفال المولودين قبل الأوان.
Next, any treatment that installs foreign objects in the body:
يلي ذلك، أي وسيلة علاجية تعتمد على وجود جسم غريب في جسم الانسان:
stents for stroke, pumps for diabetes,
الدعامات لأمراض الجلطة ومضخات (الانسولين) لمرضى داء السكري.
dialysis, joint replacements.
وغسيل الكلى، والمفاصل الصناعية.
How many athletic baby boomers need new hips and knees?
كم من شخص رياضي كبير في السن يحتاج إلى مفاصل جديدة للفخذ والركبة؟
A recent study estimates that without antibiotics,
تقدَر دراسة حديثة أنه بدون المضادات الحيوية،
one out of ever six would die.
سيموت واحد من كل ستة أشخاص.
Next, we'd probably lose surgery.
بعد ذلك ربما سنفقد الجراحة.
Many operations are preceded
كثير من العمليات يتم خلالها تقديم
by prophylactic doses of antibiotics.
جرعات وقائية من المضادات الحيوية.
Without that protection,
بدون هذه الحماية،
we'd lose the ability to open the hidden spaces of the body.
سنفقد القدرة على فتح الأماكن الخفية في الجسم.
So no heart operations,
لا مزيد من جراحات القلب،
no prostate biopsies,
أو استئصال نسيج من البروستاتا لفحصه،
no Cesarean sections.
أو ولادات قيصرية.
We'd have to learn to fear infections that now seem minor.
سيتوجب علينا الخوف من الاصابة بعدوى تبدو الآن بسيطة.
Strep throat used to cause heart failure.
بكتيريا ستريبت (تصيب الحلق) كانت تسبب فشل القلب.
Skin infections led to amputations.
عدوى الجلد كانت تؤدي إلى البتر.
Giving birth killed, in the cleanest hospitals,
الولادة كانت تؤدي إلي الموت في أنظف المستشفيات،
almost one woman out of every 100.
امرأة من كل 100 تقريبا.
Pneumonia took three children out of every 10.
ذات الرئة أو الالتهاب الرئوي تتسبب بوفاة 3 أطفال من كل 10.
More than anything else,
أهم شيء على الاطلاق،
we'd lose the confident way we live our everyday lives.
سنفقد تلك الثقة التي نعيش بها حياتنا اليومية.
If you knew that any injury could kill you,
لو علمت أن أي اصابة يمكن أن تودي بحياتك،
would you ride a motorcycle,
هل ستركب دراجة بخارية ؟
bomb down a ski slope,
هل ستتزحلق على الجليد ؟
climb a ladder to hang your Christmas lights,
أو تصعد سلم لتعليق أضواء عيد الميلاد؟
let your kid slide into home plate?
أو تدع أطفالك يلعبون البيسبول ؟
After all, the first person to receive penicillin,
في نهاية الأمر، فإن أول شخص يتلقى البنسيلين
a British policeman named Albert Alexander,
كان رجل شرطة بريطاني يدعى ألبرت الكساندر،
who was so ravaged by infection that his scalp oozed pus
كان في حالة سيئة جدا حتى أن فروة رأسه تقيحت
and doctors had to take out an eye,
واضطر الأطباء لاستئصال عينه،
was infected by doing something very simple.
كان قد أصيب بالعدوى لأنه قام بعمل بسيط جدا.
He walked into his garden and scratched his face on a thorn.
تمشى في حديقته و خدش وجهه بشوكة.
That British project I mentioned which estimates that the worldwide toll
هذا المشروع البريطاني الذى ذكرته يقدَر الحصيلة في جميع أنحاء العالم
right now is 700,000 deaths a year
الآن بحوالي 700.000 وفاة في العام
also predicts that if we can't get this under control by 2050,
ويُتوقع إذا لم يتم السيطرة على الأمر بحلول عام 2050،
not long, the worldwide toll will be 10 million deaths a year.
ليست بمدة بعيدة، فإن التعداد سيصل إلى 10 مليون وفاة في العام.
How did we get to this point
كيف وصلنا إلى هذه المرحلة
where what we have to look forward to
حيث يجب علينا أن نتنبأ
is those terrifying numbers?
بهذه الأرقام المخيفة ؟
The difficult answer is, we did it to ourselves.
الاجابة الصعبة هي أننا نحن من تسبب بذلك،
Resistance is an inevitable biological process,
المقاومة عملية بيولوجية حتمية،
but we bear the responsibility for accelerating it.
و لكن نحن من يتحمل مسئولية إسراعها.
We did this by squandering antibiotics
فعلنا ذلك عن خلال الإسراف في المضادات الحيوية
with a heedlessness that now seems shocking.
باستهتار يبدو صادما الآن.
Penicillin was sold over the counter until the 1950s.
كان البنسلين يصرف دون وصفة حتى عام 1950.
In much of the developing world, most antibiotics still are.
في أغلب الدول النامية، معظم المضادات الحيوية لا زالت كذلك.
In the United States, 50 percent
في الولايات المتحدة، 50%
of the antibiotics given in hospitals are unnecessary.
من المضادات الحيوية المعطاة في المستشفيات غير ضرورية.
Forty-five percent of the prescriptions written in doctor's offices
45% من الوصفات الطبية المكتوبة في العيادات
are for conditions that antibiotics cannot help.
لحالات طبية لا فائدة من استخدام المضادات الحيوية لمعالجتها.
And that's just in healthcare.
هذا في نظام الرعاية الصحية فقط.
On much of the planet, most meat animals get antibiotics every day of their lives,
معظم الحيوانات المأكولة تُعطى مضادات حيوية يوميا
not to cure illnesses,
ليس لعلاج الأمراض،
but to fatten them up and to protect them against
و لكن لتسمينها وحمايتها من
the factory farm conditions they are raised in.
ظروف الموجودة في المزارع الصناعية التي تُربى فيها.
In the United States, possibly 80 percent
في الولايات المتحدة، 80% تقريبا
of the antibiotics sold every year go to farm animals, not to humans,
من المضادات الحيوية المباعة سنويا تذهب إلى مزارع الحيونات، ليس للبشر،
creating resistant bacteria that move off the farm
خالقة بكتيريا مُقاومة تنتقل من المزارع
in water, in dust,
عبر الماء والغبار
in the meat the animals become.
و اللحوم التي تتحول لها هذه الحيونات.
Aquaculture depends on antibiotics too,
الزراعة السمكية تعتمد أيضا على المضادات الحيوية،
particularly in Asia,
خصوصا في آسيا،
and fruit growing relies on antibiotics
كما تعتمد زراعة الفاكهة أيضا على المضادات الحيوية
to protect apples, pears, citrus, against disease.
لحماية التفاح والكمثرى وأشجار الحمضيات من الأمراض.
And because bacteria can pass their DNA to each other
ولأن البكتيريا تستطيع أن تتبادل الأحماض النووية بين بعضها البعض
like a traveler handing off a suitcase at an airport,
كمسافر يسلّم حقيبته في المطار،
once we have encouraged that resistance into existence,
بمجرد أن أوجدنا تلك المقاومة،
there is no knowing where it will spread.
لا أحد يعلم أين ستنتشر.
This was predictable.
كان الأمر متوقع.
In fact, it was predicted
في الحقيقة، توقع هذا الأمر
by Alexander Fleming, the man who discovered penicillin.
الكسندر فيلمينج، الرجل الذي اكتشف البنسيلن
He was given the Nobel Prize in 1945 in recognition,
ونال جائزة نوبل عام 1945 عِرفاناً،
and in an interview shortly after, this is what he said:
في مقابلة تلت ذلك قال :
"The thoughtless person playing with penicillin treatment
"'الشخص الأرعن الذي يتعامل مع علاج البنسلين كأنه لعبة
is morally responsible for the death of a man
مسؤول أخلاقيا عن وفاة رجل
who succumbs to infection
تعرض لعدوى
with a pencillin-resistant organism."
ميكروب مقاوم للبنسلين"
He added, "I hope this evil can be averted."
و أضاف: "آمل أنه يمكن تفادي هذا الشر"
Can we avert it?
هل يمكن أن نتفاداه ؟
There are companies working on novel antibiotics,
هناك شركات تعمل على مضادات حيوية جديدة،
things the superbugs have never seen before.
أشياء حتى أقوى الميكروبات لم ترها من قبل.
We need those new drugs badly,
نحتاج هذه العقاقير بشدة،
and we need incentives:
كما نحتاج حوافز جديدة:
discovery grants, extended patents,
منح اكتشاف وبراءات اختراع ،
prizes, to lure other companies into making antibiotics again.
وجوائز لاستدراج الشركات لصناعة المضادات الحيوية مرة أخرى.
But that probably won't be enough.
لكن على الأرجح هذا وحده ليس كافيا.
Here's why: Evolution always wins.
إليكم السبب: التطور يربح دائما.
Bacteria birth a new generation every 20 minutes.
يظهر جيل جديد من البكتيريا كل 20 دقيقة.
It takes pharmaceutical chemistry 10 years to derive a new drug.
تستغرق الكيمياء الصيدلية 10 أعوام لاستخلاص دواء جديد.
Every time we use an antibiotic,
في كل مرة نستخدام مضادا حيويا،
we give the bacteria billions of chances
نعطي البكتيريا مليارات الفرص
to crack the codes
لفك الرموز
of the defenses we've constructed.
الدفاعية التي شيدناها.
There has never yet been a drug
حتى الآن لا يوجد دواء
they could not defeat.
لم يتمكنوا من هزيمته.
This is asymmetric warfare,
إنها حرب غير متكافئة،
but we can change the outcome.
ولكن يمكننا تغيير النتائج.
We could build systems to harvest data to tell us automatically and specifically
يمكن أن نبني أنظمة لجمع البيانات لتخبرنا تلقائياً، وعلى وجه التحديد
how antibiotics are being used.
كيف يجري استخدام المضادات الحيوية.
We could build gatekeeping into drug order systems
يمكن أن نبني نظام مراقبة على طلب الأدوية
so that every prescription gets a second look.
بحيث أن كل وصفه طبية يعاد النظر إليها.
We could require agriculture to give up antibiotic use.
يمكن أن نتخلى عن استخدام المضادات الحيوية في الزراعة.
We could build surveillance systems
يمكن أن نبني أنظمة المراقبة
to tell us where resistance is emerging next.
لإخبارنا أين تبرز المقاومة في المرة القادمة.
Those are the tech solutions.
هذه هي الحلول التقنية.
They probably aren't enough either,
و هي ليست كافية أيضا،
unless we help.
إلا إذا ساعدنا في ذلك.
Antibiotic resistance is a habit.
تعتبر مقاومة المضادات الحيوية عادة.
We all know how hard it is to change a habit.
كلنا نعرف كم هو صعب التخلي عن عادة.
But as a society, we've done that in the past.
لكن كمجتمع، فعلنا هذا في الماضي.
People used to toss litter into the streets,
اعتاد الناس رمي النفايات في الشوارع،
used to not wear seatbelts,
اعتادوا ألا يلبسوا أحزمة الأمان،
used to smoke inside public buildings.
اعتادوا التدخين في الأماكن العامة.
We don't do those things anymore.
لم نعد نفعل هذه الأمور.
We don't trash the environment
لا نلوث البيئة
or court devastating accidents
أو نتسبب بحوادث مدمرة
or expose others to the possibility of cancer,
أو نعرض الآخرين للاصابة بالسرطان،
because we decided those things were expensive,
لأننا رأينا أن هذه الأمور مكلفة،
destructive, not in our best interest.
مدمرة ولا تخدم الصالح العام.
We changed social norms.
لقد غيرنا المعايير الاجتماعية.
We could change social norms around antibiotic use too.
و يمكننا تغيير المعاييرالاجتماعية حول استعمال المضادات الحيوية أيضا.
I know that the scale of antibiotic resistance
أعلم أن هذا المدى من مقاومة المضادات الحيوية
seems overwhelming,
يبدو خطيرا.
but if you've ever bought a fluorescent lightbulb
ولكن إذا كنت قد اشتريت لمبة فلورسنت
because you were concerned about climate change,
لأنك شعرت بالقلق إزاء تغير المناخ،
or read the label on a box of crackers
أو قرأت الملصق الموجود على علبة من البسكويت
because you think about the deforestation from palm oil,
لأن تفكر في إزالة غابات للحصول على زيت النخيل،
you already know what it feels like
فأنت تعرف شعور
to take a tiny step to address an overwhelming problem.
اتخاذ خطوة صغيرة لمعالجة مشكلة عظمى.
We could take those kinds of steps for antibiotic use too.
يمكن أن نتخذ هذه الخطوات لحل مشكلة استخدام المضادات الحيوية أيضا.
We could forgo giving an antibiotic if we're not sure it's the right one.
يمكن أن تتخلى عن إعطاء مضاد حيوي في حال عدم التأكد من كونه مناسب.
We could stop insisting on a prescription for our kid's ear infection
يمكن أن نتوقف عن الإصرار على وصفة طبية لعدوى أذن لأطفالنا
before we're sure what caused it.
قبل أن نتأكد من سبب العدوى.
We could ask every restaurant,
ويمكن أن نسأل كل مطعم،
every supermarket,
وكل سوبر ماركت،
where their meat comes from.
من أين يحصلون على اللحوم.
We could promise each other
يمكن أن نعد بعضنا البعض
never again to buy chicken or shrimp or fruit
بعدم شراء الدجاج أو الجمبري أو الفاكهة
raised with routine antibiotic use,
التي تم فيها استخدام المضادات الحيوية الاعتيادية.
and if we did those things,
وإن فعلنا هذه الأشياء،
we could slow down the arrival of the post-antibiotic world.
يمكن أن نُبطئ وصول عصر ما بعد المضادات الحيوية.
But we have to do it soon.
ولكن علينا أن نفعل ذلك في وقت قريب.
Penicillin began the antibiotic era in 1943.
بدأ عصر المضادات الحيوية باستخدام البنسلين في عام 1943.
In just 70 years, we walked ourselves up to the edge of disaster.
في غضون 70 عاما، وصلنا إلى حافة الكارثة.
We won't get 70 years
لن نحصل على 70 عاما
to find our way back out again.
للعثور على طريق العودة من جديد.
Thank you very much.
شكرا جزيلا.
(Applause)
(تصفيق)